<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Christian Paulsen</title>
 <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-10-23T00:49:31-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://christianpaulsen.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Christian Paulsen</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Black Mirror S03E01&#58; Nosedive</title>
   <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/22/Black-Mirror-Nosedive/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/22/Black-Mirror:-Nosedive</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt; does a remarkable job of taking current technologies or trends and extrapolating them just to the brink of absurdity. Each episode leaves the viewer wondering whether or not it could possibly happen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nosedive&lt;/em&gt; takes the concept of digital social reputation, melds it with the ubiquity and inescapability of credit scores, and turns the whole thing up to 11. It follows one woman’s attempt at climbing the social ladder via improving her score, which results in a number of both funny and depressing interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous episodes of &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;, I felt like in this one the concept didn’t really warrant a full hour. The content of the episode felt stretched thin to fill the full hour. Also, uncharacteristic of other episodes, this one had what could loosely be interpreted as having an ending with a silver lining. Sort of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the episode still shows all the core strengths of &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;, but I hope the next episodes are better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Luther is neat</title>
   <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/19/luther-is-neat/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/19/luther-is-neat</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luther_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luther&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has been on my “to watch” list for some time now. It’s a no-brainer, really. It appeals to both my Anglophilia and my enjoyment of crime dramas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie &lt;em&gt;Se7en&lt;/em&gt; clearly influences &lt;em&gt;Luther&lt;/em&gt;. Both take place in worn out, broken down, sparsely populated, degenerate urban settings. If you enjoy those slideshows of old neighborhoods in Detroit falling apart and completely devoid of life, &lt;em&gt;Luther&lt;/em&gt; feels a lot like that. The game &lt;em&gt;Condemned: Criminal Origins&lt;/em&gt; is another point of comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One aspect that I particularly enjoyed was seeing some of London’s interior architecture. &lt;em&gt;Luther&lt;/em&gt; takes place largely in either apartment complexes or industrial areas. I don’t know how representative of London the filming locations were, but I found many of the structures interesting to look at. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bleak environment makes the deviant crimes portrayed seem less far-fetched. However, multiple times throughout the series, a criminal commits some shocking act of violence in a relatively crowded area and no one does anything. In one particular scene, a man walks into a busy office complex and begins attacking people with a hammer and squirt-gun filled with acid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, I don’t think a large group of people is quite so helpless against one man with a hammer. This begs the question, Why are people portrayed as being completely helpless against criminals? Is that a commonly held view in England? Is it lazy writing? I’m really curious what the answer could possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gilmore Ghetto</title>
   <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/18/gilmore-ghetto/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/10/18/gilmore-ghetto</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In anticipation of the new &lt;em&gt;Gilmore Girls&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve been going through a list of some of the better episodes from the original run. Broadcast from 2000-2007, it ended right around the time smartphones came out. What strikes me as interesting is how tone deaf the show is to the internet, both technologically and culturally. It reminds me of one of my favorite shows, &lt;em&gt;NewsRadio&lt;/em&gt;, which had a similar obliviousness. &lt;em&gt;NewsRadio&lt;/em&gt;, however, came out in the mid-90s, so it had a bit more of an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of it stems from the writers being out of touch with youth. You look at the way teenagers are portrayed and you realize that the teenagers you are looking at are not approximations of real life teenagers, but a bizarre projection of the adult writers’ ideal version of a teenager. For example, the genre of rap music is completely non-existent. All of the teenagers listen to punk, alternative, college rock, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t detract too much from the show, but I wonder how much change to expect in the portrayal of technology in the upcoming series. The 1990s and 2000s may have been peak internet ignorance. I’m assuming by now even the most insulated people have more or less caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Clockwork Elves</title>
   <link href="http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/02/29/clockwork-elves/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://christianpaulsen.com/2016/02/29/clockwork-elves</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, someone is speaking some truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0BKzuzjjCro&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
